SRI HARSHA CHILAKAPATI

Bengaluru, India · +91 9494607964

sriharshachilakapati@gmail.com · goharsha.com · github.com/sriharshachilakapati

A self-enthusiast developer who is interested in developing applications for platforms of interest such as Android, Web, Desktop and also iOS. Had experience in building real-time applications optimized for performance. I'm always interested in exploring tech.

EXPERIENCE

1ST OCTOBER 2019 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

JUSPAY

- Optimized Gradle build pipeline to make builds faster by 65% from 2 minutes to 13 seconds.
- Created new SDK architecture for Hyper SDK 2.0, a flagship product of Juspay.
- Created a Chrome DevTools plugin which allows debugging of native Android Views.
- Wrote 2 Gradle plugins to generate code and assets for merchants resulting in reduction of merchant specific flavours in the HyperSDK code base.

1ST JUNE 2018 – 30TH SEPTEMBER 2019

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

JUSPAY

- Part of the payment page team and worked on payment pages for Ola Money, Cred and Big Basket.
- Took ownership of Payment Pages for Foodpanda and Bounce (Android & iOS).
- Created the VIES merchant demo app (Android) at Juspay.

4TH DECEMBER 2017 – 31ST MAY 2018

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEERING INTERN

JUSPAY

- Implemented 2 screens (Settings & User Profile) in BHIM UPI App.
- Part of the 4-person team and created the first payment page prototype for Goibibo.
- Worked on Android module of Presto UI called Mystique, which is a React Native like framework for Juspay.

3RD MAY 2017 - 9TH JUNE 2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

MIRACLE SOFTWARE SYSTEMS

- Created a Help Desk ticketing system for company employees using Material Design in a team of 6.
- It uses NLP APIs from IBM Watson to analyze the tone of the message and decides ticket priority based on keywords.

JUNE 2017 – 30TH NOVEMBER 2017

TEACHING ASSOCIATE, SVEC TECHNICAL CLUB

PROJECTS

- Yoda Shop (Android app to manage home deliveries)
- SilenceEngine (Game Engine for Desktop, HTML5 and Android)
- WebGL4J (WebGL bindings for Java language using GWT)
- GWT-AL (An OpenAL implementation on top of Web Audio API)
- YT Private Subscriptions (iOS App that allows to subscribe to YT channels without logging in)
- <u>EasyJSON (Easy to use small (11 KB) JSON library for Java)</u>
- EasyXML (Easy to use small (13 KB) XML library for Java)

SKILLS

PROFICIENT IN

Java, Kotlin, JavaScript, Swift, PureScript, Android Development, iOS Development

FAMILIAR WITH

C, C++, C# and 24 other Programming Languages

CAN SPEAK IN

Telugu, English, Hindi, Kannada, Tamil

CAN READ & WRITE IN

Telugu, Latin, Kannada, Devanagari, Tamil

EDUCATION

MAY 2021

IOS DEVELOPER NANODEGREE, UDACITY

FEB 2021

ANDROID KOTLIN DEVELOPER NANODEGREE, UDACITY

EXPECTING IN 2021

B. TECH IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, SVEC